Guide to the Community Service Society Archives
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series XV: Files, 1960-1970
  - minutes of subcommittees, 1962-1963 (Box 466)
  - Clippings, 1960s (Box 467-469)
  - Publications by and about CSS: (Box 467-470)
    - Committee on the Prevention of TB, 1903-1916 4v. (Box 467-470)
    - Social Work as Human Relations, 1949 (Box 467-470)
    - In Memoriam, Josephine Shaw Lowell, 1906 (Box 467-470)
    - Tenement House Committee Reports, 1899-19l6 (Box 467-470)
    - Kasius, Cora: Relief Practice in a Family Agency, 1942 (Box 467-470)
    - Marcus, Grace F.: Some Aspects of Relief in Family Casework, 1929 (Box 467-470)
    - Shetland, Margaret L.: Family Health Service, 1943 (Box 467-470)
  - Brandt, Lilian: (Box 471)
    - The C.O.S 1907 (Box 471)
    - Growth and Development of AICP and COS, 1941 (Box 471)
  - CSS Annual Reports, 1960-1970 (Box 471)
  - Scrapbook, 196O-1965 (Box 471)
  - Miscellaneous Printed material (Box 471)
- Series XVI: Historical Data, 1970 & Following
  - Subseries XVI.1: Historical Data
    (Contains some files dating back to 1939)
    - Abortion (Box 472)
    - Access Project I 1974-2/77, II 3/77-7/78, "Aid to Consumers Concerning Entitled Support Services" (Box 472)
    - Accounting Department (Box 472)
    - Administration: (Box 472)
    - Correspondence, Charles Langdon, Alvin Schorr, et al 1976 ff (Box 472)
    - Memos 1970 ff (Box 472)
    - Advisory Committee Report 12/15/76 Eliot D. Hawkins, Chairman (Re: Relations between Trustees and Officers, the General Director and Staff and the Volunteer Committees. With Minority Report re: Alvin Schorr by Jewelle W. Bickford a.k.a. "Hawkins Committee") (Box 472)
    - Advocates for Children (Proposed program of New York State Division for Youth thru New York City Youth Bureau offering after school employment and help with school functioning to 300 14-17 year olds referred to Family Court, 1978. With United Automobile Workers.) (Box 472)
    - Affirmative Action (also in Personnel: Equal Opportunity Hiring) (Box 472)
    - Aging: (Box 473)
      - Lecture Series "Horizons for Later Life" 1972 (Box 473)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 473)
      - Symposium on Alternatives to Institutional Care for the Elderly, etc., 1975 (Box 473)
      - Services Described to Gerontology Meetings 1974-1978 Hunter College Colloquium (Box 473)
      - See also Aging: Horizons for Later Life (Box 473)
      - CASC (Box 473)
      - Committee on Aging (Box 473)
      - Crime Against the Elderly (Box 473)
      - Frail Elderly (Box 474)
      - Friendship Center (See also: Jamaica Service Program for Older Adults, Older Persons Services, RSVP, etc.) (Box 474)
    - Aliens, Undocumented - Task Force 1978 (Box 475)
    - Anniversary, Hundredth - Publication of Symposia (Box 475)
    - Anniversary, 25th - Symposium 1974 (Box 475)
    - Annual Meeting 12/14/77 - Addressed by Bertram Beck as "recently named General Director" (Box 475)
    - Annual Meetings (Box 476)
    - Annual Report Digest 1983-1984 (Box 476)
    - Application Service (Box 476)
    - Archives
      - Case records (Box 476)
      - Committee (Box 476)
      - General (Box 476)
      - Lists AICP and Cos (Box 476)
      - Gifts and Accessions (Box 476)
      - Photos (Box 476)
      - Requests for Use, Folder I (A-P) (Box 476)
      - Requests for Use, Folder II (Q-Z) (Box 477)
      - Theses (Box 477)
      - Transferred to Columbia University Library, Lists kept at CSS: AICP and COS; CSS 1939-1960, 1960-1970 ff (Box 477)
    - Automobile Lease and Insurance 1979-1980 (Box 477)
    - Bilingual Education:
      - General (Box 477)
      - Districts, Information (Box 477)
      - Districts 1, 3, 5, 7, 9, 11, 13, 15 (Box 477)
      - Districts 17K, 19, 21, 23, 27, 29, 31 (also in Reports Section) (Box 478)
    - Board Information Folder - Sample (First Edition 3/78) Re: information for Trustees. Also see: "Retreat" and Trustees, Board of (Box 478)
    - Brooklyn - Office (Box 478)
    - BUCCS (Budget & Credit Counseling Service), Folder I - 1976-78, Folder 2 - 1970 ff (Box 478)
    - Budget (of CSS) 1975-1985 I to 5/82 (Box 478)
    - Budget (of CSS) II, and III (Box 479)
    - Budget Committee (Box 479)
    - Budget Handbook Family Services 1975 (Box 479)
    - Bulletin of CSS:
      - 6 covers 1914-1961 (Box 479)
      - "Happy Birthday" 1964 (50th) Copies in Reports Section (Box 479)
    - By-Laws - changes 1939 ff, 1971, 1976, 1978, 1979, 1980 (Box 479)
    - Cable TV re: Open Access 1982 (Box 479)
    - Cafeteria for CSS (Box 479)
    - CAMP - See vacation (Box 479)
    - Case Records - COS Records copied by University of Pennsylvania Student 1982. Also see Group Therapy in Reports Section. (Box 480)
    - Case Record Retention Policy (Box 480)
    - Casework, Shift from Practice of, 1971 (Box 480)
    - CAUSE (Community Association United in Service for Everyone) 1973-1978 Folders 1-4 (Box 480)
    - CAUSE Folder 5 (Box 481)
    - CETA (Comprehensive Employment Training Act) 1977-1980 (Box 481)
    - CHELSEA Inter-Agency Council "CIAC, " 1978 (Box 481)
    - Child Abuse, 1976-1978 (Box 481)
    - Child Care - Informal 1976-1978 also see: Reports Section: I (Box 481)
    - Child Care - Mobicentrics on...1976-1977 (Box 482)
    - Chinatown Services to, 1971 ff (Box 482)
    - Chinatown 25th Anniversary Banquet 4/21/71 (Box 482)
    - Chinatown Planning for - see: Schilt Report in Report Section (Box 482)
    - Chinatown Mental Health Programming for (Box 482)
    - City, (CSS) Department of (Box 482)
    - City Mission Society 1977 (Box 482)
    - Citywide Coalition of Community Boards (Box 482)
    - Clippings - Miscellaneous 1975 ff (Box 482)
    - Collaboration - see: Community Council re: it and State Charities Aid with CSS (Box 482)
    - Columbia Library Columns - November 1982 Volume XXXII No. 1 re: old CSS (AICP and COS) records given to the Library and February 1982 Volume XXXI No. 2 Pg. 37 re: CSS additional gift of "nearly 70,000" pieces of correspondence, etc. dating from Merger 1939. (Box 482)
    - Columbia University Library see also: Archives Transferred to... (Box 482)
    - Commissions - Guidelines and Chart 1/1982 and 1981 (Box 483)
    - Committee Lists 1979 ff (Box 483)
    - Committees Fee Committee - see in "F", Pilot Survey re: Fees for Casework Service 1949 (Box 483)
    - Committees, Program - formerly "Survival Issues Committee" 1978-1981 (Box 483)
    - Committees, Planning and Research (Box 483)
    - Community (Planning) Board Project - I 1976-4/1977 - II 4/1977-6/1978 (Box 483)
    - Community Care Facilities (Box 483)
    - Center, Jack Varick, et al (Box 483)
    - Community Council (Box 484)
    - Development Department 1983 (Box 484)
    - Department and Community Services Department Organizing (Box 484)
    - Community Organizing (Box 484)
    - Community Supports Commission - see: Three-Year Plan (Box 484)
    - Computer Services, Office of (Box 484)
    - Confidentiality:
      - Supreme Court Decision 1967 ff (Box 484)
      - Gladys Baer vs. The Welfare Inspector General, 1978 (Box 484)
      - New York Appellate Division Ruling 1978 (Box 484)
    - Consolidated Edison - re: Possible neighborhood economic development co-sponsored with CSS 2/80. Also see: Economic Development Neighborhoods 1979 (Box 484)
    - Consolidation, Certificate of 1939 and Amendment 1980 (AICP, COS, CSS) (Box 484)
    - Consultants (Box 484)
    - Consumer Participation - Draft by Thelma Stackhouse of proposed statement 1977 39 pp. and parts of other proposed statements of the subject. Fragmentary. (Box 484)
    - Consumer Protection (Box 484)
    - Continuing Services 1976-1977 (Box 484)
    - Contributions, Tax Exemption of, and Miscellaneous, including monies contributed by CSS. (Box 484)
    - Contributors - Examples: Dean, Guggenheimer, Moore, Page, et al (Box 484)
    - Corporate Meeting Minutes - 6/16/82 and Corporate Information Booklet 10/80 (Box 484)
    - Counsel (Box 484)
    - "CRESAP" Report 1981 - Correspondence re: role of volunteers in policy formation (Box 484)
    - Crime Against the Elderly, 1977-1980 see: Aging (Box 484)
    - Criminal and Juvenile Justice:
      - Curriculum at John Jay College included (Box 484)
      - Coalition on Criminal and Juvenile Justice (Box 484)
    - Data Processing: Design proposal for Project JOEY, et al (Box 485)
    - Day Care Study, 1977, 1982 (fragmentary) (Box 485)
    - Default Judgements (Box 485)
    - deForest, Robert Portrait by Cicelia Beaux in General Director's Office (Box 485)
    - deForest, Robert. Study of: "Four Ways of Looking at a Philanthropist" by James A. Hijiya 12/80 (Box 485)
    - DAMP (Box 485)
    - Department Heads' Meetings with Bertram Beck 1978-1979 (Box 485)
    - Direct Mail Solicitation (Box 485)
    - Direct Service:
      - Beck Memo to File 3/1978 2 1/2 pp. (Box 485)
      - Unsigned Mimeographedd Memo of 1/10/75 (Box 485)
      - Committee Meeting 3/16/76 (Box 485)
    - Direction Service - 1977-1978 for families with handicapped children - in independent status renamed "Synergia" (Inc.) providing "professional expertise and mutual help groups to solve overwhelming family problems." (Box 485)
    - Disabled Children (Box 485)
    - Divorce Reform 1967
      - Plea to the Legislature (Box 485)
      - Committee on Youth, Correction, Department of Public Affairs, January 1967 (Box 485)
    - Drug Abuse (Box 485)
    - East Harlem Interfaith Welfare Committee 1980 (Box 486)
    - East Harlem Planning Statement - Thelma Stackhouse A/1911 (Box 486)
    - Economic Development; of Neighborhoods 1979 - A proposal that CSS assist therein (Box 486)
    - Education (Committee) and Education Miscellaneous Statements 1974-1978 (Box 486)
    - Employee Relations (ex-Personnel) 1978 (Box 486)
    - Employment:
      - Sub-committee 1977 (Box 486)
      - Procedures (Box 486)
      - General (Box 486)
    - Employment - "Chasing the American Dream", Dale Mann 1980 see: Reports (Box 486)
    - Equal Employment Program - see: Personnel, Equal Opportunity Hiring (Box 486)
    - Endowed Funds and Bequests 1977 ff (Box 486)
    - Ethics - also see: Confidentiality (Box 486)
    - Executive Committee for Planning, Executive Committee for Administration (Box 486)
    - Ex-Offenders Employment, 1972-1974 A Project of Committee on Volunteer Programs (Box 486)
    - Family Court Proposed - Mental Health Service 1977 ff (Box 486)
    - Family Day Care, A Proposal, 1976 (Box 486)
    - Family and Individual Well-Being Department 1978 ff (Box 487)
    - Family Service Association of America II: "Family Advocacy" (Box 487)
    - Family Service Project, South Bronx 1982 (Box 487)
    - Family Service Time Study Research Project, Public Health Nursing Section 1957-1958 (Box 487)
    - (Fall) Fashion Show 1973 (Box 487)
    - Federal Fund Applications (Box 487)
    - Fee Committee - Pilot Survey 1949 (Many references, client's names must be disguised) (Box 487)
    - Fellows - Fellow in Government: Paul du Brul 1/78 (Box 487)
    - Financial Assistance 1974, 1976, 1977, 1978 (Box 487)
    - Financial Investment Policy 1978-1979 (Box 487)
    - Financial Statements 1973 ff (Box 487)
    - Fiscal Policy (Box 487)
    - Fiscal Year: 7/1-6/30 - By-Law 1978 (Box 487)
    - Floor Plans - 105 East 22nd Street 1975 (Box 488)
    - Focus and Direction - Task Force 1984-1985 (Box 488)
    - Food Stamps and Food Assistance, Food Miscellaneous (Box 488)
    - Foster Care: Rate Study 1977 ff: Structure and Functions (Box 488)
    - Foundations Support (Box 488)
    - Foundations Miscellaneous (Box 488)
    - Friendship Center 10/77-4/80, 10/76-9/77, 11/72-10/76 (Box 488)
    - Public Relations see: Aging (Box 488)
    - Fund for the City of New York (Box 488)
    - Fund Raising - Sample Contributor Correspondence (Box 488)
    - Funds - Restricted and Unrestricted (Box 489)
    - General 1977 ff: Structure and Functions (Box 489)
    - General Director - Miscellaneous (Box 489)
    - General Directory - Deputy and Assistant (Box 489)
    - General Directory - Evaluation of his performance 1982-1985 (Box 489)
    - General Programs and Issues Committee: 1977 Project on City Governance (Box 489)
    - General Services, Office of (Box 489)
    - Goldberg, Gertrude S., Correspondence re: Dissertation 1975 "New Directions for the CSS of NY: A Study of Organizational Change" (Ms. in Reports Section) (Box 489)
    - Government Funds (Box 489)
    - Governments, Local and Urban Problems (Box 489)
    - Greater New York Fund 1970-1978 (Box 489)
    - Griggs, Emily - Fund in the New York Community Trust 1954-1963 (Box 490)
    - Grosvenor House - Proposal and Collaboration, 1975 (Box 490)
    - Group Health Insurance (Box 490)
    - Haitian Entrants and Haitian Refugee Assistance Program (Box 490)
    - Handicapped Children - Proposal to Identify Problems and Needs 49 pp. ca. 1980 (Box 490)
    - Hawkins Committee - see: Advisory Committee (Box 490)
    - Health Committee (Box 490)
    - Correspondence (Box 490)
    - Position Statements (Box 490)
    - Health Benefits (for Staff) 1975, 1979 (Box 490)
    - History of CSS: (Box 491)
      - *Highlights 1948-1959 and "Basic Purposes," Charts and Summary descriptions of program, 1948 (*Duplicates, originals at Columbia) (Box 491)
      - Criticisms of Lilian Brande's "Growth and Development of AICP and COS," Q.V. in Reports Section (Box 491)
      - History Folder I re: Bright and other possible writers; Folder II Miscellany re: Bright Ms. (Box 491)
      - Oral History 1980-1981 filed Reports Tousley and Randall (Box 491)
      - 1971-1973 re: Brandt's Growth and Development of AICP and COS, 1942 which CSS more or less repudiated (Box 491)
      - Sallie E. Bright's unfinished Ms. See in Reports also V. herein I (Box 491)
    - History Oral - Davies' at Columbia University (to be copied for CSS) (Box 491)
    - Home Attendant Training 1977-1978 (Box 491)
    - Home Care 1973-1978 see: Aging (Box 491)
    - Homeless - also see Reports "Private Lives...", "One Year Later" (Box 491)
    - Homeless Youth - see Youth (Box 491)
    - Hospitals, Municipal: Recommendations 1978 Review 11/1977 (Box 491)
    - Housing, Enriched, For the Elderly - 1978-1979, 1982 (Box 492)
    - Housing Statement - Re: Museum of Modern Art Proposal 1977 and Other Statements - Housing Committee (Box 492)
    - Housing and Urban Development - Sub-committee (also see Department of Alternative Management Programs "DAMP") (Box 492)
    - Housing and Urban Development Members (in the 70s): (Box 492)
    - H.U.D. Correspondence (Box 492)
    - See Committee on H.U.D. Legislation in New York State 1974, 1973 (Box 492)
    - Minutes in "Reports" (Box 492)
    - Human Resources Administration (ex. Welfare Department) and Human Services 1971 (Box 492)
    - Hundred Year Association - CSS admitted 1/30/48 (Box 492)
    - Immigration, Naturalization (Box 492)
    - Information Center (Box 492)
    - Information and Referral (includes Storefront Venture) (Box 492)
    - Information Directories Listed (Box 492)
    - Initiatives Proposed 1978 ff (Box 493)
    - Insurance, Varieties CSS Carries - 1978 (Box 493)
    - Investments (Box 493)
    - Jamaica Service Program for Older Adults (JSPOA):
      - Folder #1: 4/72 - 12/74 (Box 493)
      - Folder #2: 1/75 - 12/76 (Box 493)
      - Folder #3: 1/77 - 12/79 ff (Box 493)
      - Folder #4: JSPOA Publicity 2/73 - 3/79 (Box 494)
      - Folder #5 Transition Proposal (Box 494)
      - Folder #6 JSPOA Printed Materials (Box 494)
    - Jobs and Economic Development Committee 1978-1979 (Box 494)
    - JOEY, Project (Job Opportunities and Education for Youth) 1978-1980 also see: Data Processing (Box 494)
    - JOEY Admission Records 1978-1979 - Confidential (Box 494)
    - Junior Committee Handbook, etc. 1970 (Box 494)
    - Junior League of New York (Box 494)
    - Junior Month, 1919-1922 - Omitted from earlier lists see: Tousley Memoir (Box 494)
    - Justice for Youth - The Courts for Wayward Youth in New York City by Bernard C. Fisher for CSS Bureau of Public Affairs, 1955 $1.00, 154 pp., with other bound books (Box 495)
    - Juvenile Justice Project "Return" (Wilderness Project) (Box 495)
    - Large Grievances about Small Causes: New York City's Small Claims Court - Special committee on consumer protection, 1974 see: Small Claims Court (Box 495)
    - Law and Lobbying (Box 495)
    - Lawyers Committee (Box 495)
    - Lay-Staff Relationships - Seminar 1975 (Box 495)
    - Legacies (Box 495)
    - Legislation - Miscellaneous 1975 ff (Box 495)
    - Liability, 1978 Correspondence (Box 495)
    - Library, Central (Box 495)
    - Library of Russell Sage Foundation, Gift of COS - Copies, historic (Box 495)
    - Literacy (Box 495)
    - Loan Project of Junior Committee 1972-1975 (Box 495)
    - Loan Program of Fund for the City of New York (Using CSS loan capital) 1982 (Box 495)
    - Lower East Side Family Union 1974-1975 (Box 496)
    - Mailing Lists - Regulation of (Box 496)
    - Management Information System - see: Statistics (Box 496)
    - Mediation/Conflict Resolution Project - A Proposal 1978 (Box 496)
    - Members (of CSS) 1977, 1979 (Box 496)
    - Mentally Disabled, Rehabilitation Services for the:
      - Community Support System NYC (Box 496)
      - Conceptual Framework 11/78 (Box 496)
      - NY State Office of Mental Health (Box 496)
    - Merger, AICP-COS, all extra copies (Box 496)
    - Merger Certificate of Consolidation and Amendments (AICP and COS) (Box 496)
    - Metropolitan Applied Research Center (MARC) 1969-1971 - Suggested by CSS Study Data Bank (Box 496)
    - Mini-Sink Townhouse (A Camp) - A unit of City Mission Society located in Harlem, "reorganizing" in 1975 (Box 496)
    - Minority Contractors Assistance Project, Inc. 1980 and "MESBIC" (Minority Enterprise Small Business Investment Corp.) (Box 496)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 496)
    - National Conference on Social Welfare (Box 496)
    - National Supports also see: Reports Section (Box 496)
    - Neighborhood Health Centers, etc. - Papers in Reports Section (Box 497)
    - Nestle Boycott (Box 497)
    - New Alternative Movement ("NAM") - Technical assistance to 9/83 (Box 497)
    - New York Charter Revision 1975-1977 re: Community Boards et al (Box 497)
    - New York City Budget and New York State Budget (Box 497)
    - New York City Department of Social Services and New York State Department of Social Services (Box 497)
    - New York Community Trust (Box 497)
    - New York Times Neediest Cases 1972 ff (Box 497)
    - Nominating Committee 1977-1984 (Box 497)
    - Office Space (Box 497)
    - Office Services - Payment of Bills 1977-1978 (Box 497)
    - Officers: Meetings - Names 1970-1982 (Box 498)
    - Older Persons Service 1971-1979 (Box 498)
    - Older Persons Service Project: Senior Entitlement Service 1976-1977 (Box 498)
    - Opportunity Shop (Thrift Shop) 1975-1979 (Box 498)
    - Organization Charts 1983 and the 1970s (Box 498)
    - Organizations - Miscellaneous (Box 498)
    - Pension Benefits (Staff) (Box 498)
    - Pension Plan (Staff) (Box 498)
    - Personal Social Services 1979 (Box 498)
    - Personalities (Separate Folders): (Box 499)
      - Baer Jr., Harold (Box 499)
      - Beck, Bertram M. (also in "Confidential", "Speeches", etc. (Box 499)
      - Bright, Sallie E. (Box 499)
      - Burden Family (Box 499)
      - Burns, Eveline (died 9/2/85) (Box 499)
      - Davies, Stanley P. (died 4/5/85) (Box 499)
      - Emerson, James G., Jr. (Box 499)
      - McMurray, Georgia (Box 499)
      - Schorr, Alvin L. (Box 500)
      - Tousley, Clare M., (died 1/21/85) (Box 500)
    - Personalities Miscellaneous (Box 500)
    - Personalities Miscellaneous Non-Professional Staff: longevity (Box 500)
    - Personnel:
      - Personnel Department Miscellaneous (Box 500)
      - Practices Committee (Box 500)
      - Practices Manual (Box 500)
      - Report of Industrial Relations Counselors Service 1960 (Box 500)
      - Staff Lists (Box 500)
      - Union see: Union for Staff: (Box 501)
      - Grievances (Box 501)
      - Kaffeeklatsches (Gab sessions with G.D.) (Box 501)
      - Staff Lists (Box 501)
      - Personnel Practices Manual Redrafting (Box 501)
      - Linda Franklin (Box 501)
      - Position Classification (Box 501)
    - Planning/Study Sessions of Staff and Trustees (May - June 1977) (Box 501)
    - Plays-For-Living Script for "Divide and Multiply" 1978 - for CSS (Box 501)
    - Policy Data Information System 1978 (Box 501)
    - Pooled Income Fund (Box 501)
    - Prescription Drugs (Box 501)
    - Press Releases, Miscellaneous (Box 501)
    - "Privatization and The Welfare State" 1985 Seminar (Box 501)
    - Process Shop, Office of Printing and Duplication (Box 501)
    - Professional Education - Intramural 1970 ff (Box 501)
    - Program Committee - See: Committees, Program and Survival Issue (Box 501)
    - Program Proposed 1977-1985 (Box 501)
    - Program - Progress (Box 501)
    - Program of CSS Described 1975-1976 Schorr (Box 502)
    - Program Division (Box 502)
    - Program Planning and Office of P.P. and Research (Box 502)
    - Public Affairs Department:
      - Committees of 1975-1977 (Box 502)
      - Positions taken by Committees on Legislation 1971-1973 (Box 502)
      - General and Miscellaneous 1971 ff (Box 502)
      - Overview 1977 (Box 502)
      - Program 1960 (Box 502)
    - Public Assistance (also see: Welfare - Department of Social Services) (Box 502)
    - Public Funds, Use of by CSS (Box 503)
    - Public Relations and Support:
      - Miscellaneous (Box 503)
      - Campaign Miscellaneous (Box 503)
      - Correspondence (Box 503)
    - Public Relations Policy: (Box 503)
    - Committees 1970 (Box 503)
    - Public Interest Committees 1978 (Box 503)
    - Public Interest Department (Box 503)
    - Public and Voluntary Welfare (Box 503)
    - Publications Lists (Box 503)
    - Purchasing and Stockroom (Box 503)
    - Queens Office: Opened 3/80 for Queens and Staten Island Staff of Department for Community and RSVP (Box 503)
    - Radio Spot Announcement and Radio Publicity and TV (Box 503)
    - REAL, Project (Return to Employment and Learning ) - Elsewhere cited as Education, 1980-1981 (Box 503)
    - Reorganization - 1978-1979 ff (Box 503)
    - Reorganization - Comment (Box 504)
    - Reports (see: separate section of file) (Box 504)
    - Research - Miscellaneous and Books in R. Department Library (Box 504)
    - Retarded Persons - Group Homes (Box 504)
    - Resources Directory (By Pat Friedland) 1984 (Box 504)
    - Retirement (Box 504)
    - "Retreat" of Board at Pawling 1983 (Box 504)
    - Riker's Island (Box 504)
    - RSVP (Retired Senior Volunteer Program): (Box 505)
      - 2 1972-1981 ff (Box 505)
      - 2 Recognition Days (Box 505)
      - 1 Advisory Committee (Box 506)
      - 1 Action Award (Box 506)
    - Salaries (Box 506)
    - Scheidlinger Bequest (Box 506)
    - Scheidlinger, Dr. Saul (Box 506)
    - Security - Safety on the job (Box 506)
    - Senior Entitlement Service 1973 ff (Box 506)
    - Senior Action Line (Box 506)
    - SERVE (Serve and Enrich Retirement by Volunteer Experience):
      - Miscellaneous 1970 (Box 506)
      - National Volunteer Award 1971 (Box 506)
      - Tribute Day 1971-1974 (Box 507)
      - Tribute Day 1975-1976, 1978 (Box 507)
      - Volunteer Training Institute 1971-1972 (Box 507)
    - SERVE/RSVP Advisory Committee 1975-1979 (Box 507)
    - SERVE in New York State 1970-1971 (Box 507)
    - Services to Individuals and Families Committee (Box 507)
    - Single Room Occupancy (Box 507)
    - Single Parent Family Project:
      - General (Box 507)
      - Publicity and Promotion (Box 508)
    - Small Claims Court (Box 508)
    - Small Claims Publicity Campaign (Box 508)